Register of the Alvin H. Scaff Papers, 1936-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
Alvin H. Scaff Papers,
1936-1954
72010
Scaff, Alvin H.
2 manuscript boxes, 4 envelopes 1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoranda, reports, diaries, photographs, and printed matter, relating to the communist movement in the Philippines, and to Japanese prison camps in the Philippines during World War II. Used as research material for the book by A. H. Scaff, The Philippine Answer to Communism (1955)
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Hukbong Mapagpalaya ng Bayan (Philippines); Communism; Communism--Philippines; Prisoners of war; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Philippines; World War, 1939-1945--Prisoners and prisons; Philippines
Biographical Note
Scaff, Alvin H., 1914-
1914, Dec. 27 Born, Dallas, Texas
1936 B.A., University of Texas with highest honors
1940 B.D., Chicago, Theol. Seminary
1940 Ordained to ministry Congregationalist Church
1941-45 Missionary Silliman University, Philippines
1946 M.A., University of Texas
1946 Instructor sociology, University of Texas
1953-54 Fulbright Research grantee, Philippines
1956 Professor of sociology, Pomona College
Series Description
- Memoranda, Reports, and Resolutions; Diary, Parodies, and Poems, ca. 1936-1954. (Box Box No. 1.)
  Typescript memos, reports, and resolutions collected in the Philippines between 1953-1954 mainly from communists captured by the Philippine Army, and used for Mr. Scaff's book The Philippine Answer to Communism. Diary (typewritten manuscript), written in Los Banos Internment Camp, Philippines. Group of parodies and poems written and sung in the same camp.
- Subject File, ca. 1949-1954. (Box Box No. 2.)
  Posters, proclamations, pamphlets, leaflets, and newspaper clippings pertaining to Philippine political and economic problems, arranged alphabetically by subject.
Container List
- Memoranda, Reports, and Resolutions; Diary, Parodies, and Poems, ca. 1936-1954.
  - Milestones in the History of the CPP, by Jose Lava., 12 pp. (Box 1.)
    (Typescript copy of the mimeographed material used by the communist party in its Huk training schools, a document captured by the Philippine Army).
  - Twenty years of Struggle of the CCP, by Gregorio Santayana (alias of Jose Lava)., 24 pp.
  - Basic National Problems and an Outline of Viable Solutions (Jose Lava: read by Senator Recto). 16 pp. Jan. 14, 1954.
  - Memorandum to Gen. Douglas MacArthur and Pres. Osmena (Luis M. Taruc, Commander-in-Chief, Hukbalahap). Paper carried by Quirino Abad Santos and 2 others to Osmena in attempt to get better understanding for and end persecution of the Huks)., 3 pp.
  - Resolution of the Banal Guerrilla Forces, Feb. 16, 1947 (Jose Banal), 28 pp.
  - Memorandum: On the Causes of and Solution to Dissidence in the Philippines, for Information in the Official Records of the Court, in the Case of People vs. Lava, et. al. Submitted by Jose Lava., 43 pp.
  - Strategy and Tactics. Author probably Jose Lava, 1950., 61 pp.
  - Our Enemy, Philippine Army pamphlet (based on captured Huk documents and mimeographed for intelligence briefing purposes), 42 pp. Attached; Bibliography on Communism in the Philippines, 8 pp.
  - Our Enemy; Philippine Army pamphlet. Chapter VI: Biographies, pp. 70-130, based on self-analysis by communist party members, documents among those captured from the Huks.
  - Labor Organizations in the Philippines,1902-1935, by Patricio Dionisio. 24 pp. (A typescript copy of an unpublished report by a special investigator for the Department of Labor, The Philippines, 1936).
  - Pomeroy's Own Story, (unpublished account captured by the Philippine Army at the time of the capture of Pomeroy).
  - Diary; Los Banos Internment Camp, Philippines, August 7, 1944 - April 1, 1945, by Alvin H. Scaff. Ms. (Typescript)
  - Group of parodies and poems written and sung in Los Banos Internment Camp, Philippines, during the last two months of internment. Collected by Alvin H. Scaff.
- Subject File, ca. 1949-1954.
  - Agrarian problems (clippings, pamphlet, reports, 1952-54). (Box 2.)
  - Huk propaganda and government replies (posters, proclamations, pamphlets, leaflets, news clippings).
  - Huks (clippings, 1952).
  - Huks (clippings, 1953).
  - Huks (clippings, 1954).
  - Magsaysay, President Ramon (clippings, 1952-1954).
  - Philippine election, 1949 (clippings, leaflets).